[
    {     
        "id":"01",
        "question": "Gule wa Mkulu also known as 'the Great Dance' is a traditional dance popular among which tribe?",
        "options": [
          "Tumbuka",
           "Chewa",
           "Sena",
          "Lomwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Chewa",
        "category": "traditional"
      },

      { "id":"02",
        "question": "Likhuba is a traditional dance popular among which tribe??",
        "options": [
           "Tumbuka",
           "Chewa",
           "Sena",
           "Lomwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Sena",
        "category": "traditional"
      },
      { "id":"03",
        "question": "Tchopa is a traditional dance popular among which tribe??",
        "options": [
           "Yao",
           "Chewa",
           "Sena",
           "Lomwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Lomwe",
        "category": "traditional"
      },
      { "id":"04",
        "question": "Manganje is a traditional dance popular among which tribe?",
        "options": [
           "Yao",
           "Chewa",
           "Sena",
           "Lomwe"
        ],
        "answer": "Yao",
        "category": "traditional"
      },
      { "id":"05",
        "question": "Mulakho wa Alomwe is an annual festival that was founded by?",
        "options": [
           "Peter Muthalika",
           "Leston Muli",
           "Bungu Muthalika",
           "George Chaponda"
        ],
        "answer": "Bungu Muthalika",
        "category": "traditional"
      },
      { "id":"06",
        "question": "What is Malawi's major ethnic group?",
        "options": [
           "Tumbuka",
           "Lomwe",
           "Yao",
           "Chewa"
        ],
        "answer": "Chewa",
        "category": "traditional"
      },    
      {	
        "id":"07",
        "question": "Who composed and wrote Malawi's National Anthem?",
        "options": [
           "Dr. Hastings Kamuzu Banda",
           "Michael-Fredrick Paul Sauka",
           "John Chilembwe",
           "Aaron Gadama"
        ],
        "answer": "Michael-Fredrick Paul Sauka",
        "category": "history"
      },  
      {	
        "id":"08",
        "question": "When was Professor Bingu wa Mutharika the president of Malawi?",
        "options": [
           "2005 to 2012",
           "2004 to 2011",
           "2004 to 2012",
           "2004 to 2013"
        ],
        "answer": "2004 to 2012",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"09",
        "question": "When did Dr. Hestings Kamuzu Died?",
        "options": [
           "1996",
           "1997",
           "1998",
           "1999"
        ],
        "answer": "1997",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"10",
        "question": "When did Malawi hold its first multi-party elections?",
        "options": [
           "17 June 1994",
           "17 May 1994",
           "17 July 1994",
           "17 May 1995"
        ],
        "answer": "17 May 1994",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"11",
        "question": "When was Bakili Muluzi the president of Malawi?",
        "options": [
           "1995 to 2005",
           "1994 to 2003",
           "1994 to 2004",
           "1993 to 2003"
        ],
        "answer": "1994 to 2004",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"12",
        "question": "When was Joyce Banda the president of Malawi?",
        "options": [
           "2012 to 2014",
           "2011 to 2013",
           "2013 to 2014",
           "2012 to 2013"
        ],
        "answer": "2012 to 2014",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"13",
        "question": "When was Prof.Peter Muthalika the president of Malawi?",
        "options": [
           "2014 to 2019",
           "2014 to 2020",
           "2013 to 2020",
           "2012 to 2019"
        ],
        "answer": "2014 to 2020",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"14",
        "question": "The politician George Chaponda has been a minister for following minisries except?",
        "options": [
           "Ministry of Agriculture, Irrigation and Water Development",
           "Ministry of Defence",
           "Ministry of Justice and Constitutional Affairs",
           "Ministry of Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation"
        ],
        "answer": "Ministry of Defence",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"15",
        "question": "The politician, Gwanda Chakwamba died in which year?",
        "options": [
           "2012",
           "2013",
           "2019",
           "2016"
        ],
        "answer": "2016",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"16",
        "question": "Who introduced Christianity in Malawi?",
        "options": [
           "John Chilembwe",
           "Dr. Kamuzu Banda",
           "Prophet Shepherd Bushiri",
           "Dr. David Livingstone"
        ],
        "answer": "Dr. David Livingstone",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"17",
        "question": "From which country did Malawi gained its independence?",
        "options": [
           "Portugal",
           "The United Kingdom",
           "United States of America",
           "Russia"
        ],
        "answer": "The United Kingdom",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"18",
        "question": "Televion Malawi(TMV) currently known as MBC TV was opened in which year?",
        "options": [
           "1995",
           "1999",
           "2000",
           "1998"
        ],
        "answer": "1999",
        "category": "general"
      },
      {
        "id":"19",
        "question": "Professor Bingu wa Mutharika left UDF and formed his own party (DPP), in which year?",
        "options": [
           "2004",
           "2005",
           "2006",
           "2007"
        ],
        "answer": "2005",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"20",
        "question": "Who was the first female Cheif Justice of the Malawi Judiciary?",
        "options": [
           "Anastasia Msosa",
           "Jane Ansah",
           "Joyce Banda",
           "Catherine Gotani Hara"
        ],
        "answer": "Anastasia Msosa",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"21",
        "question": "Everton Chimulirenji was the Vice President for Malawi in which years?",
        "options": [
           "2018 - 2020",
           "2019 - 2020",
           "2017 - 2019",
           "2018 - 2019"
        ],
        "answer": "2019 - 2020",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"22",
        "question": "On which day do Malawians celebrate Kamuzu Day?",
        "options": [
           "13 May",
           "14 May",
           "15 January",
           "03 March"
        ],
        "answer": "14 May",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"23",
        "question": "On which day do Malawians celebrate independence Day?",
        "options": [
           "6 June",
           "6 July",
           "03 March",
           "7 June"
        ],
        "answer": "6 July",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"24",
        "question": "On which day do Malawians remember Rev.John Chilembwe?",
        "options": [
           "13 January",
           "03 March",
           "15 January",
           "16 January"
        ],
        "answer": "15 January",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"25",
        "question": "On which day do Malawian celebrate the Martyrs' Day?",
        "options": [
           "02 March",
           "03 March",
           "04 March",
           "15 January"
        ],
        "answer": "03 March",
        "category": "general"
      },
      {
        "id":"26",
        "question": "When did Lilongwe became the capital city of Malawi?",
        "options": [
           "1965",
           "1966",
           "1975",
           "1976"
        ],
        "answer": "1975",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"27",
        "question": "When was Queen Elizabeth Central Hospital in Blantyre opened?",
        "options": [
           "1954",
           "1964",
           "1958",
           "1968"
        ],
        "answer": "1968",
        "category": "history"
      },
      {
        "id":"28",
        "question": "What is the nickname for Malawi's national netball team?",
        "options": [
           "The Flames Queens",
           "The Malawi Flames",
           "The Malawi Queens",
           "The Copper Queens"
        ],
        "answer": "The Malawi Queens",
        "category": "sports"
      },      
      {
        "id":"29",
        "question": "In sport, NAM stands for what?",
        "options": [
           "Netball Alliance of Malawi",
           "Netball Associates in Malawi",
           "Netball Association of Malawi",
           "National Association of Malawi"
        ],
        "answer": "Netball Association of Malawi",
        "category": "sports"
      },      
      {
        "id":"30",
        "question": "In sport, When was Bingu National Stadium opened?",
        "options": [
           "2015",
           "2016",
           "2017",
           "2018"
        ],
        "answer": "2017",
        "category": "sports"
      },
      {
        "id":"31",
        "question": "What is the real name for the comedian - Manganya?",
        "options": [
          "Born Kalindo",
          "Michael Usi",
          "Eric Mabedi",
          "John Nyanga"
        ],
        "answer": "Michael Usi",
        "category": "entertainment"
      },
      {
        "id":"32",
        "question": "Who is the current president of Malawi?",
        "options": [
           "Chakwera",
           "Chilima",
           "Muluzi",
           "Bingu"
        ],
        "answer": "Chakwera",
		    "category": "general"
      },
      {
        "id":"33",
        "question": "How many districts are in Malawi?",
        "options": [
           "31",
           "28",
           "30",
           "32"
        ],
        "answer": "28",
		    "category": "general"
      },
      {
        "id":"34",
        "question": "How many regions are in Malawi?",
        "options": [
           "Two",
           "Five",
           "Four",
           "Three"
        ],
        "answer": "Three",
		    "category": "general"
      },
      {
        "id":"35",
        "question": "What was the total population for Malawi at the time of census in 2018?",
        "options": [
           "13,066,320",
           "9,933,868",
           "17,563,749",
           "20,091,635"
        ],
        "answer": "17,563,749",
		    "category": "general"
      },
      {
        "id":"36",
        "question": "How many districts are in Malawi's central region?",
        "options": [
           "Eleven",
           "Eight",
           "Seven",
           "Nine"
        ],
        "answer": "Seven",
		    "category": "general"
      },
      {
        "id":"37",
        "question": "What is the real name for the Musician - Piksy?",
        "options": [
           "Evans Zangazanga",
           "Zangazanga Chikhosi",
           "Peter Zangazanga",
           "Nicholus Mbonera"
        ],
        "answer": "Evans Zangazanga",
		    "category": "entertainment"
      },   
      {
        "id":"38",
        "question": "Shire river is in the following districts except?",
        "options": [
           "Nsanje",
           "Mangochi",
           "Chikwawa",
           "Ntcheu"
        ],
        "answer": "Ntcheu",
		    "category": "general"
      },
      {
        "id":"39",
        "question": "What is the name of Malawi's first female speaker of Parliament?",
        "options": [
           "Esther Cheka Chilenje",
           "Calister Muthalika",
           "Catherine Gotani Hara",
           "Monicca Chakwera"
        ],
        "answer": "Catherine Gotani Hara",
		    "category": "general"
      },
      {
        "id":"40",
        "question": "What does the rising sun on the Malawi flag represent?",
        "options": [
           "Dawn of freedom and hope",
           "Unity",
           "Warm heart of Africa",
           "Freedom"
        ],
        "answer": "Dawn of freedom and hope",
		    "category": "general"
      },
      {
        "id":"41",
        "question": "Malawi is shares international borders with the following countries, except?",
        "options": [
           "Zambia",
           "Tanzania",
           "Zimbabwe",
           "Mozambique"
        ],
        "answer": "Zimbabwe",
		    "category": "general"
      },
      {
        "id":"42",
        "question": "In Football, SULOM stands for?",
        "options": [
           "Sports League of Malawi",
           "Super League of Malawi",
           "Standard-Bank League of Malawi",
           "Superior League of Malawi"
        ],
        "answer": "Super League of Malawi",
		    "category": "sports"
      },
      {
        "id":"43",
        "question": "In Football, FAM stands for?",
        "options": [
           "Football Administration in Malawi",
           "Football Alliance in Malawi",
           "Football Association of Malawi",
           "Football Attachment of Malawi"
        ],
        "answer": "Football Association of Malawi",
		    "category": "sports"
      },
      {
        "id":"44",
        "question": "Hospitals Owned by Religions are Called CHAM Hospitals, CHAM Stands for?",
        "options": [
           "Churches Health Association of Malawi",
           "Churches Hospital Alliance of Malawi",
           "Christian Hospitals Alliance of Malawi",
           "Christian Health Association of Malawi"
        ],
        "answer": "Christian Health Association of Malawi",
		    "category": "general"
      },
      {
        "id":"45",
        "question": "ADMARC stands for?",
        "options": [
           "Agricultural Development and Marketing Company",
           "Agricultural Development and Marketing Committe",
           "Agricultural Development and Marketing Corporation",
           "Agricultural Development and Marketing Council"
        ],
        "answer": "Agricultural Development and Marketing Corporation",
		    "category": "general"
      },
      {
        "id":"46",
        "question": "What is the name of the hydropower plant that was destroyed in 2022 by cyclone storm ANA?",
        "options": [
           "Nkula A",
           "Kapichira",
           "Tedzani",
           "Nkula B"
        ],
        "answer": "Kapichira",
		    "category": "general"
      },
      {
        "id":"47",
        "question": "In which district is lake Chirwa found?",
        "options": [
           "Mangochi",
           "Chikwawa",
           "Zomba",
           "Balaka"
        ],
        "answer": "Zomba",
		    "category": "general"
      },  
      {
        "id":"48",
        "question": "In which district is lake Malombe found?",
        "options": [
          "Mangochi",
          "Chikwawa",
          "Zomba",
          "Balaka"
        ],
        "answer": "Mangochi",
		    "category": "general"
      },  
      {
        "id":"49",
        "question": "According to 2018 NSO Census, Which district has the highest population?",
        "options": [
           "Mzimba",
           "Blantyre",
           "Lilongwe",
           "Mangochi"
        ],
        "answer": "Lilongwe",
		    "category": "general"
      },
      {
        "id":"50",
        "question": "According to 2018 NSO Census, Which region has the highest population?",
        "options": [
           "Northern Region",
           "Central Region",
           "Southern Region"
        ],
        "answer": "Southern Region",
		    "category": "general"
      },     
      {
        "id":"51",
        "question": "On which day do Malawians commemorate freedom day?",
        "options": [
           "14 June",
           "14 July",
           "14 July",
           "14 May"
        ],
        "answer": "14 June",
		    "category": "general"
      },
      {
        "id":"52",
        "question": "Which of the following traditional dances is popular among the Ngoni poeple?",
        "options": [
           "Tchopa",
           "Ingoma",
           "Likhuba",
           "Manganje"
        ],
        "answer": "Ingoma",
		    "category": "traditional"
      },
      {
        "id":"53",
        "question": "Which of the following traditional dances is popular among the Tonga people of Nkhatabay district?",
        "options": [
           "Malipenga",
           "Tchopa",
           "Gule wa Mkulu",
           "Manganje"
        ],
        "answer": "Malipenga",
		    "category": "traditional"
      },
      {
        "id":"54",
        "question": "What's the name of the Lomwe paramount chief who died in 2019?",
        "options": [
           "Mkhumba",
           "Lundu",
           "Ngwenyama",
           "Ngongoliwa"
        ],
        "answer": "Ngongoliwa",
		    "category": "traditional"
      },
      {
        "id":"55",
        "question": "What's the title for the paramount chief for Chitipa and Karonga District?",
        "options": [
           "Kyungu",
           "Chikulamayemba",
           "Mbelwa",
           "Lundu"
        ],
        "answer": "Kyungu",
		    "category": "traditional"
      },
      {
        "id":"56",
        "question": "What's the title for the paramount chief for the lower shire (Nsanje and Chikwawa)?",
        "options": [
           "Kyungu",
           "Chikulamayemba",
           "Mbelwa",
           "Lundu"
        ],
        "answer": "Lundu",
		    "category": "traditional"
      },
      {
        "id":"57",
        "question": "When did Malawi first participated in the Africa Cup of Nations (AFCON)?",
        "options": [
           "1984",
           "1994",
           "1974",
           "1964"
        ],
        "answer": "1984",
		    "category": "sports"
      },
      {
        "id":"58",
        "question": "Who is the all time top scorer for the Malawi national football team (scored 71 goals in 115 games)?",
        "options": [
           "Fisher Kondowe",
           "Gabadinho Mhango",
           "Kinnah Phiri",
           "Lawrence Waya"
        ],
        "answer": "Kinnah Phiri",
		    "category": "sports"
      },
      {
        "id":"59",
        "question": "Which football club is also known as - The Peoples Team / Maule?",
        "options": [
           "Wanderers",
           "Silver Strikers",
           "Civo United",
           "Big Bullets"
        ],
        "answer": "Big Bullets",
		    "category": "sports"
      },
      {
        "id":"59",
        "question": "Which football club is also known as - The Nomads / Nyerere?",
        "options": [
           "Wanderers",
           "Silver Strikers",
           "Civo United",
           "Big Bullets"
        ],
        "answer": "Wanderers",
		    "category": "sports"
      },
      {
        "id":"60",
        "question": "Which Malawian football club has won most championships under the Super League of Malawi (SULOM) title?",
        "options": [
           "Wanderers",
           "Silver Strikers",
           "Civo United",
           "Big Bullets"
        ],
        "answer": "Big Bullets",
		    "category": "sports"
      },
      {
        "id":"61",
        "question": "Which Malawian football club was formed in 1967 by a group of players from Wanderers?",
        "options": [
           "Big Bullets",
           "Silver Strikers",
           "Civo United",
           "Blue Eagles"
        ],
        "answer": "Big Bullets",
		    "category": "sports"
      },
      {
        "id":"62",
        "question": "In a movie - Last Fishing Boat, What's the real name for Yusufu (Mustafa's Father)?",
        "options": [
           "Robert Kaluwa",
           "Hope Chisanu",
           "Shemu Joyah",
           "Steven Maseya"
        ],
        "answer": "Hope Chisanu",
		    "category": "entertainment"
      },
      {
        "id":"63",
        "question": "In a malawian Tikuferanji drama, What's the real name for Nginde?",
        "options": [
           "Winiko",
           "Bon Kalindo",
           "Michael Usi",
           "Frank Yalu"
        ],
        "answer": "Frank Yalu",
		    "category": "entertainment"
      },
      {
        "id":"64",
        "question": "In the Malawian Tikuferanji tv drama, What's the real name for Make Sikono?",
        "options": [
           "Ruth Seko",
           "Ruth Maseko",
           "Ruth Simika",
           "Ruth Mika"
        ],
        "answer": "Ruth Simika",
		    "category": "entertainment"
      },
      {
        "id":"65",
        "question": "Who is the founder of the Black Missioneries Band?",
        "options": [
           "Robert Fumulani",
           "Musamude Fumulani",
           "Anjiru Fumulani",
           "Evison Matafale"
        ],
        "answer": "Evison Matafale",
		    "category": "entertainment"
      },
      {
        "id":"66",
        "question": "When did Evison Matafale Died?",
        "options": [
           "2000",
           "2001",
           "2002",
           "2003"
        ],
        "answer": "2001",
		    "category": "entertainment"
      },
      {
        "id":"67",
        "question": "Who is the founder of the Zodiak Malawi TV and Radio station?",
        "options": [
           "Joab Frank Chakhaza",
           "Brian Banda",
           "Gospel Kazako",
           "Gospel Kasakula"
        ],
        "answer": "Gospel Kazako",
		    "category": "entertainment"
      },
      {
        "id":"68",
        "question": "What's the real name for the musician Onesmus?",
        "options": [
           "Armstrong Kalua",
           "Armstrong Kamwendo",
           "Armstrong Kumwenda",
           "Armstrong Kaliu"
        ],
        "answer": "Armstrong Kalua",
		    "category": "entertainment"
      },
      {
        "id":"68",
        "question": "Which Malawian artist released the song Vinyo watha in 2022?",
        "options": [
           "Piksy",
           "Mlaka Maliro",
           "Lucius Banda",
           "Anthony Makondetsa"
        ],
        "answer": "Mlaka Maliro",
		    "category": "entertainment"
      }

  
      
]